Tyler Degand

Web Developer

Self-motivated Web Developer adds fresh perspective to web-based products through development experience. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customized interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability and security. Pulls from active knowledge of current technology landscape to promote best practices in web design.



Work History

Oct 2020 -Current

Full Stack Web Developer

PurpleWave Inc, Manhattan KS

- Worked with a team of developers using Scrum to solve problems and develop new parts of the system.
- Worked with a variety of technologies front end to back end to build, maintain and debug software/websites.

July 2019 -Oct 2020

Technical Support Engineer

CivicPlus, Manhattan KS

- I worked with client websites in troubleshooting and maintaining
 content
- Troubleshoot issues with how users implement content, work with and escalate bugs and minor design issues using knowledge of HTML, CSS and JavaScript.



Education

2020-03 -Current

TechDegree: Full Stack JavaScript Development

Team Treehouse - Online

Full Stack Development course with popular languages and frameworks such as JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Pug, React, SQL and much more. **Slack Champion:**

Was an active member of the community that answered questions on code and reviewed other student projects to find errors and bugs.



Accomplishments

CivicPlus-

Bronze Stevie Award - The Stevie Awards

Feb 2020

Customer Service Training or Coaching Program of the Year - Technology Industries

Silver Stevie Awards - The Stevie Awards

Feb 2020

Front-Line Customer Service Team of the Year - Technology Industries



Contact

Address

Manhattan, KS, 66502

Phone

7853411595

E-mail

tylerdegand@gmail.com

WWW

https://www.tylerdegand.com

linkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-degand-21252bb9/



Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React

Node.js

Express.js

Sequelize

MySQL

SQL

Pugjs (Jade)

Git

Nginx

Software Debugging

Performance Optimization